他们不必经常输球，你对今天的失败有何分析？
They don't have to lose often, what is your analysis of today's defeat?
No les toca perder a seguido, ¿cuál es tu análisis de la derrota de hoy?
你的意见是什么？
What is your opinion?
¿ Cuál es su opinión?
然后我认为在游戏中必须有一个团队
and then I think that in the game there had to be a team
y después creo que el partido sí tuvo que haber un equipo
在点球大战中。
in the penalty game.
en la partida del penal.
玩的很少，我们没有机会这样做
Very little has been played and we have not had the opportunity to do
Se ha jugado muy poco y no hemos tenido la posibilidad de hacer
发生什么事了？
What's happening?
¿Qué pasa?
发生什么事了？
What's happening?
¿Qué pasa?
怎么了？
what is happening?
¿ que es lo que está pasando?
他说我们祝贺哥伦比亚获胜，并且......
He said that we congratulate Colombia, who won and...
Decía que felicitamos a Colombia, que ganó y...
我认为我们打了一场精彩的比赛……
and I think we played a good game in line with...
y nosotros creo que hicimos un buen partido acorde con...
以我们来玩的情况。
with the circumstances that we came to play.
con las circunstancias que vinimos a jugar.
没什么可说的，好吧，它已经丢失了，我们必须抬起头，就像我们常说的那样。
and little more to say, well, it was lost, we have to raise our heads, as we always say.
y poco más que decir, bueno, se perdió, hay que levantar cabeza, como siempre decimos.
并继续，但我认为球队的路线是积极的，超越......
and continue, but I think the team's line was positive, beyond...
y seguir, pero la línea del equipo creo que fue positiva, más allá de...
失败的时候，我想我们一直都在露脸，我们甚至可以
of the defeat, I think we showed our faces at all times, we could even
de la derrota, creo que dimos la cara en todo momento, pudimos incluso
赢得比赛不仅是平局，而且还包括裁判看到的点球，
winning the game not only tying it but well that penalty play that the referee saw and
ganarlo el partido no sólo empatarlo pero bueno esa jugada de penal que el árbitro ha visto y
从那时起，就很少有人玩了。
From then on very little has been played.
A partir de ahí se ha jugado muy poco.
莱昂内尔，你来塔兹体育怎么样？
Lionel, how are you here for Taze Sports?
Lionel, ¿cómo estás acá para Taze Sports?
你谈到了点球大战，你看起来很生气，你和裁判以及教练组交谈。
You talked about the penalty play, you looked angry and you talked to the referee, also the coaching staff.
Hablaste de la jugada del penal, se te vio enojado y hablaste con el árbitro, también el cuerpo técnico.
你对那场比赛有什么看法？你对皮耶罗·马萨说了些什么？
What do you think about that play and what did you say to Piero Massa?
¿Qué considerás de esa jugada y qué le dijiste a Piero Massa?
从某种意义上说，我们不喜欢失败，但就是这样，就是这样，因为如果不是以后
in the sense that we don't like to lose but that's it, that's what it is because if not later
en el sentido de que no nos gusta perder pero ya está es lo que hay porque si no después
我们说我们不知道如何失去，我们确实知道如何失去，这伤害了我们。
We say that we don't know how to lose, we do know how to lose, it hurts us.
decimos que no sabemos perder, sí que sabemos perder, nos duele.
我还对穆尼奥斯说的唯一一件事，我认为在图像中可以看到，是整个球场上唯一没有抗议的球员是他。
The only thing I also said to Muñoz, which I think was seen in the images, was that the only player on the entire field who did not protest is him.
Lo único que le dije también a Muñoz, que creo que se vio en las imágenes, fue que el único jugador que no protestó de toda la cancha es él.
他们已对他处以罚款。
that they have charged him the penalty.
que le han cobrado el penal.
没什么可说的，有时轮到你了，有时轮到我们了。
and little more to say, sometimes it's your turn, sometimes it's up to us.
y poco más que decir, a veces te toca por un lado, a veces toca para nosotros.
以及有什么，但令人悲伤的是，不幸的是
and what there is, but it is sad, it is unfortunate that
y lo que hay, pero es triste, es lamentable que
判罚后比赛实际上还没有进行。
that after the penalty the game has practically not been played.
que después del penal prácticamente el partido no se ha jugado.
这只是让我烦恼的一点，而不是处罚。
That's a little what bothered me, not so much the penalty.
Eso es un poco lo que a mí me molestó, no tanto el penal.
游戏还没有玩过，那很好。
The game has not been played and that's good.
no se ha jugado el partido y bueno es lo que
这就是我所看到的，但是嘿，总的来说，哥伦比亚的胜利应该值得祝贺，仅此而已。
That's what I saw, but hey, in general, Colombia's victory should be congratulated and that's it.
Es lo que vi yo, pero bueno, en general el triunfo de Colombia hay que felicitarlo y ya está.
上半场阿根廷有抗议胡安吗？
Did Argentina protest Juan in the first half?
¿Argentina protestó a Juan en primer tiempo?
市中心。
downtown.
en el centro de la ciudad.
在夜晚的框架内。
in the framework of the night.
en el marco de la noche.
这是如何影响的？
How did that impact?
¿ cómo repercutió eso?
我不知道哥伦比亚人民是否喜欢我谈论炎热天气，但我不是在谈论炎热天气本身，而是在谈论比赛的时间。
I don't know if the people of Colombia liked me talking about the heat, but I'm not talking about the heat itself, but about the time of the game.
No sé si le ha gustado a la gente de Colombia que yo hable del calor, pero yo no hablo del calor en sí, sino del horario del partido.
这是两个不同的事情。下半场比赛不是为了表演。
They are two different things. The time of the game is not for a show. The second half was seen.
son dos cosas diferentes el horario del partido no es para un espectáculo se ha visto el segundo tiempo un
一场人们喜欢看的比赛，仅此而已。
a game that people like to watch, nothing more.
un partido que a la gente le guste ver, nada más.
两者的热量是相同的。
The heat is the same for both.
El calor es igual para los dos.
比赛日程不对。
The game schedule is not right.
El horario del partido no está bien.
下午五点、六点、七点可以玩。
You can play at five, six, seven in the afternoon.
Se puede jugar a las cinco, seis, siete de la tarde.
这就是它的味道。
That's what it smells like.
Eso es lo que huele.
为了足球运动员的发展
for footballers to develop
para que los futbolistas desarrollen
这不是借口，我之前就说过了
It's not an excuse, I said it before
no es una excusa, lo dije antes
事情就是这样，但是那些决定的人，我不知道比赛时是谁决定的，当然......
It is what it is, but those who decide, I don't know who decide at the time of the game, surely...
Es lo que hay, pero los que deciden, que no sé quiénes son los que deciden en el horario del partido, seguramente...
在这种情况下，是哥伦比亚，好吧，他们已经决定了，就是这样，但很明显，条件并不......
In this case it is Colombia, well, they have decided this and that's it, but it is evident that the conditions are not...
en este caso sea Colombia, bueno, han decidido esto y ya está, pero es evidente que las condiciones no...
看一场好戏并不好，尤其是两场选秀
to see a good show is not so good, especially two selections that
para ver un buen espectáculo no es tan buena, sobre todo dos selecciones que
感谢上帝，他们在分类中名列前茅，他们需要......
Thank God they are up there in the classification and they need...
Gracias a Dios están ahí arriba la clasificación y necesitan...
积分不多，他们需要比赛，但这并不是哥伦比亚赢得胜利的借口
of the points not so much and they need their game but it is not an excuse sincerely Colombia has won and
de los puntos no tanto y necesitan de su juego pero no es excusa sinceramente Colombia ha ganado y
至于点球大战……嗯……
And as for the Penalty play... well,...
y en cuanto a la jugada de Penal... bueno, de...
Julián's 确实在那里留下了巨大的足迹。
Julián's does have a huge footprint there.
El de Julián sí que tiene ahí un pisotón enorme.
我没有看朱利安的完整电影，这就是我没有看到的。
I don't see Julián's full movie, that's what I don't see.
Yo no veo full de Julián, eso sí que no veo.
别的事以后再说吧。
The other thing later.
Lo otro después.
但裁判吹响了全场，然后……
but the referee whistled full and took full and then...
pero el árbitro pitó full y cobró full y después...
戏已经结束了，仅此而已。
The play was over and nothing more.
Se terminó la jugada y nada más.
我没什么好说的，我再说一遍，有时候是我们这边，这次不是另一边，我们必须……
I don't have much to say, I repeat, sometimes it's on our side, this time it wasn't on the other side, we have to...
No tengo mucho para decir, repito, a veces toca del lado nuestro, esta vez no tocó del otro lado, hay que...
低下头继续前进，因为事实上，稍后如果你多说一句话，他们总是会在那里关注
bow your head keep moving forward because it is also true that later if you say one more word they are always there attentive to
agachar la cabeza seguir para adelante porque también es verdad que después si decís una palabra de más siempre está están ahí atento para
所以他不会留在监狱里
so he doesn't stay in jail
para que no se quede en la cárcel
总统，总统先生。
President, Mr. President.
Presidente, señor presidente.
你的意见是什么？
What is your opinion?
¿ Cuál es tu opinión?
他不习惯失败。
He is not used to losing.
no está acostumbrado a perder.
你得到了哪些积极的方面？
What positive aspects do you get?
¿Qué aspectos positivos sacás?
他们说，从这次失败中，教练从失败中学到的东西比从胜利中学到的更多。
From this defeat, they say that coaches learn more from defeats than from victory.
de esta derrota, dicen que de las derrotas los técnicos aprenden más que de la victoria.
一如既往，球队的竞争超越了结果。
As always, the team competes beyond results.
Lo de siempre, el equipo compite más allá de resultados.
我们进入半场输球。
We went into halftime losing.
Nos fuimos al descanso perdiendo.
当比赛比分接近时我们打平了，因为我认为从那时起球队
We tied when the game was close on our side because I think that from then on the team
empatamos cuando el partido estaba parecido para nuestro lado porque creo que a partir de ahí el equipo ya
他感觉舒服多了，点球大战到来了，我们在比赛中从来没有丢过面子。
He felt much more comfortable, the penalty play came, we never lost face in the game.
se encontró mucho más cómodo, viene la jugada del penal, nunca perdimos la cara el partido.
除了最后一场比赛之外，我相信他们在最后一刻进行了一场一对一的比赛。
Beyond the last play, I believe that in the last minute they had a one-on-one match.
más allá de la última jugada creo de ellos que en el último minuto que tuvieron una in mano a mano.
团队就在那里，我们总是有非常清晰的情况，尽管它们最终并没有非常接近地实现。
The team was there, we always had quite clear situations, although they did not end up materializing very close to the
el equipo estuvo ahí siempre tuvimos situaciones bastante claras aunque no se terminaron a concretar muy cerca del
进球，这才是最重要的。
to score a goal and that is the important thing.
de hacer gol y eso es lo importante.
有时你没有获胜，但这种情况下的感觉是积极的。
There are times when you don't win, but the feelings in this case are positive.
Hay veces que no se gana, pero las sensaciones en este caso son positivas.
我们还必须谈论对手，他是一个伟大的对手，一支伟大的球队，而且踢得很好。
and we also have to talk about the rival, who is a great rival, a great team and who plays well.
y también hay que hablar del rival, que es un gran rival, un gran equipo y que juega bien.
莱昂内尔，你好吗？
Leonel, how are you doing?
Leonel, ¿cómo te va?
尼古拉斯·梅 (Nicolás May) 效力于 Cadena 3 和 Central Deportiva。
Nicolás May for Cadena 3 and Central Deportiva.
Nicolás May para Cadena 3 y la Central Deportiva.
两个查询。
Two queries.
Dos consultas.
首先，今天发生的事情让你最困扰的是什么？
First, what bothers you the most about what happened today?
La primera, ¿qué es lo que más te molesta de lo que pasó hoy?
另一个，
and the other,
y el otro,
的球员。
of the players.
de los jugadores.
他们可能已经到了极限，或者直接被排除在与委内瑞拉的比赛之外。
that they could be just at the limit or directly left out of the match with Venezuela.
que podían quedar justamente al límite o directamente quedarse fuera del partido con Venezuela.
你知道吗？
Do you know something?
¿Sabes algo?
我不知道谁吃到黄牌，我总是很快地进更衣室。
I don't know who got a yellow card, I always got into the locker room quickly.
No sé a quién le sacó amarilla, yo me metí siempre al vestuario rápido.
而且这个游戏让我很困扰。
and that the game bothered me.
y que me molestó el partido.
不，呃，实际上...
No, well, actually...
No, bueno, en realidad...
如果我必须专注于某件事，那就是点球大战，但好吧，就是这样，他看到了点球。
If I have to focus on something it is that penalty play, but well, that's it, he saw a penalty.
Si me tengo que fijar en algo es en esa jugada del penal, pero bueno, ya está, él vio penal.
他和……酒吧里有多少人？
him and the... how many are there in the bar?
el y los... ¿cuántos hay en el bar?
¿辛科？
¿Cinco?
是的，酒吧里的每个人。
Yes, everyone in the bar.
Sí, todos en el bar.
酒吧里的五个人呢？
And the five from the bar?
¿Y los cinco del bar?
其余的部分...
The rest...
El resto...
老实说，并不是我没有看到点球，我注意到，足球是一项运动
Honestly, it's not that I don't see a penalty, I notice, football is a sport
yo sinceramente no es que no veo penal, yo me fijo, el fútbol es un deporte
你还必须多看看你周围发生的事情，你周围的事情。
You also have to look a lot at what's going on around you, what surrounds you.
que también hay que mirar mucho lo que pasa alrededor, lo que te rodea.
穆尼奥斯的所作所为已经告诉了你一切。
And what Muñoz did tells you everything.
Y lo que hizo Muñoz te dice todo.
他任何时候都不会抗议，但欢迎加入他的团队。
He doesn't protest at any time, but welcome to his team.
no protesta en ningún momento, pero bienvenido para su equipo.
好吧。
Alright.
Está bien.
这就是我在球场边告诉他的话。
That's what I told him on the edge of the court.
Eso fue lo que le dije al borde de la cancha.
唯一没有抗议的就是你，他笑了。
The only one who didn't protest was you and he laughed.
El único que no protestaste fuiste vos y se reía.
嗯，就是这样。
Well, that's it.
Bueno, ya está.
你不必考虑太多。
You don't have to give it much thought.
no hay que darle mucha vuelta.
如果这确实影响了比赛，那么判罚显然会影响我们之后的表现。
If it is true that it conditions the match, the penalty obviously conditions us afterwards.
Si es verdad que condiciona el partido, el penal condiciona, es evidente, nosotros después.
但我们没有这么做。
but we didn't do it.
pero no lo hicimos.
最重要的是，在心理层面上，他们给了他们动力，也给了我们动力。
Above all, on a psychological level, they gave them a boost, they gave us a boost.
sobre todo a nivel psicológico a ellos le dieron un empujón, a nosotros
发生的一切让我们更加紧张，但我仍然认为我们有机会扳平比分
With everything that happened it made us a little more nervous and well still I think we had a chance to tie it
con todo lo que pasó nos puso un poquito más nerviosos y bueno aún así creo que tuvimos para para empatarlo
此刻
at the moment in which
en el momento en el que se
对你来说，哥伦比亚的胜利公平吗？
For you, was Colombia's victory fair?
para usted, ¿ fue justo el triunfo de Colombia?
你能这样看吗？
Can you look at it like that?
¿ lo pueden mirar así?
罪犯。
offender.
delincuente.
好吧，他们赢了，我们祝贺他们，有时
well and they won we congratulate them there are times when
bueno y ganaron lo felicitamos hay veces que
比赛的分析在打平的时候就决定了很多，这是由这种类型的比赛决定的。
that the analysis of a match is decided a lot when they are tied, it is decided by this type of play.
que el análisis de un partido se decide mucho cuando están igualados, se decide por este tipo de jugada.
结果就是这样。
and in the end that's what happened.
y al final eso fue lo que pasó.
就这样决定了，当然……
It was decided like this and surely...
Se decidió así y seguramente...
我们做了最困难的事情，那就是打结。
We did the most difficult thing, which was to tie it.
Nosotros hicimos la más difícil que fue empatarlo.
从那时起，我相信，我重复一遍，这场比赛对我们来说比对他们来说更重要，那个点球决定了比赛。
From there I believe, I repeat, that the game was more for us than for them, that penalty decided the game.
a partir de ahí que creo, repito, que el partido estaba más para nosotros que para ellos, ese penal decidió el partido.
我们必须祝贺哥伦比亚，它赢了，除此之外别无其他。
We must congratulate Colombia, which won and little else.
Hay que felicitar a Colombia que ganó y poco más.
您在寻找什么
What were you looking for with the
¿ que buscaba con los
在这种情况下，你总是试图获胜或平局，改善球队，寻找新的变体。
You always try to win or draw in this case, improve the team, look for new variants.
Siempre se intenta ganar o empatar en este caso, mejorar el equipo, buscar nuevas variantes.
这就是我们所尝试的。
and that is what is attempted.
y eso es lo que se intenta.
还没有玩过太多
that has not been played much
que se haya jugado no mucho
球场上的质量，你看重什么
of quality on the pitch, what things do you value
de calidad en la cancha, ¿qué cosas valora
不，他有很好的球员，他有很好的球员。
No, he has good players, he has good players.
No, tiene buenos jugadores, tiene buenos jugadores.
老实说，这不仅仅是像赛前所说的那样，死球。
Honestly, it's not just, as was said before the game, the dead ball.
Sinceramente no es solo, como se decía antes del partido, la pelota parada.
一点也不。
Not at all.
Para nada.
他有一位出色的足球运动员，他必须让事情继续下去。
He has a great footballer and he has to get things going.
Tiene un gran futbolista y tiene que aceitar un funcionamiento.
他们做得很好。
and they do it well.
y lo hacen bien.
在这里与他们比赛非常复杂。
It is enormously complex to play against them here.
Tiene una enorme complejidad jugar acá contra ellos.
祝贺你。
to congratulate you.
que felicitarlo.
您好，斯卡罗尼教授、劳尔·瓦里特、蓬托拉科鲁尼亚。
Greetings, Professor Scaloni, Raúl Varite, Punto Deportivo.
Corrie el saludo, profesor Scaloni, Raúl Varite, Punto Deportivo.
你认为这场比赛有可能打平吗？
Do you think this match could be tied?
¿ usted cree que este partido se podría empatar?
此刻
at the moment in which
en el momento en el que se
如果我想我可以把它系在巴兰基亚
If I thought I could tie it here in Barranquilla
si pensaba que lo podía empatar aquí en Barranquilla
你总是充满希望，我认为我们必须这样做，但它没有发生
you always always have hope and I think we had to do it and it didn't happen
siempre siempre se tiene la esperanza y creo que tuvimos para hacerlo y no se dio
眼下。
at the moment.
en este momento.
但这是不可能的
but it has not been possible
pero no se ha podido
的足球节。
of the football festival.
de la fiesta del fútbol.
您如何解释像您的世界冠军或美洲杯冠军这样的球队到来的现象？
How do you interpret this phenomenon of the arrival of a team like yours, world champion, or Copa América champion?
¿Cómo interpreta este fenómeno de la llegada de una selección como la suya, campeona del mundo, bien campeón de la Copa América?
我们举办的这个聚会
and this party we had
y esta fiesta que hemos tenido
此时帮助我们的善意
the kindness of assisting us at this time
la gentileza de atendernos a esta hora
巴兰基亚人民支持他们的团队，支持他们的选择。
The people of Barranquilla are for their team, for their selection.
La gente de Barranquilla está para su equipo, para su selección.
我们在酒店受到了很好的接待，但是当我们来到体育场时......
We had a good reception at the hotel, but when we came to the stadium...
Hemos tenido un buen recibimiento en el hotel, pero cuando vinimos al estadio ya...
友谊消失了一点，但是，嘿，这很正常，这是每个人都......
The friendship disappeared a little, but hey, it's normal, it's something that everyone...
La amistad un poco desapareció, pero bueno, es normal, es algo que todo el mundo...
他希望他的球队获胜，但是……
He wants his team to win, but...
Quiere que gane su equipo, pero...
他们很高兴，因为我们赢得了世界冠军，这是值得赞赏的。
They are happy because we have won the world championship and that is appreciated.
están contentos porque nosotros hemos ganado el campeonato del mundo y eso es de agradecer.
球的。
of the ball.
de la bola.
同样的失败
of the same defeat
de la misma derrota
但他的团队坚持认为
but his team maintains that
pero su equipo mantiene esa
在当地条件下或在以下条件下不改变、不放弃
that is not changed, is not renounced in local condition or also in condition of
que no se cambia, no se renuncia en condición de local o también en condición de
我们总是尝试打造现代的传球路线
we always try to have a modern line through the ball
intentamos siempre tener una línea moderno a través del balón
然后最后几米，好吧，尝试......
and then the last meters, well, try...
y después los últimos metros, bueno, intentar...
努力做到有效，这是我们今天没能做到的，但沿着思路
Try to be effective, something we have not been able to do today, but along the lines
Intentar ser efectivo, cosa que hoy no hemos podido, pero en la línea
团队就是这样，我们不会改变它，也不会从逻辑上纠正现有的东西来改进。
The team is what it is, we are not going to change it and logically correct the things that exist to improve.
el equipo es la que hay, no la vamos a cambiar y corregir lógicamente las cosas que hay para mejorar.
谢谢！
¡Gracias!
事件的受害者。
of the victims of the events.
de las víctimas de los hechos.
在酒吧里，酒吧本身
in the bar, the bar as such
en el bar, el bar como tal se
不，我相信什么，如果我必须说一件事的话......
No, what I believe and if I have to say one thing...
No, yo lo que creo y si tengo que decir una cosa...
我总是这么说，但不是现在，我不知道我是否在新闻稿中说过，但我确实……
I always said it, it's not now, I don't know if I ever said it in a press release, but I do...
que siempre la dije, no es ahora, no sé si alguna vez la dije en rola de prensa, pero sí que a mí me...
我希望看到这一点有所改善。
I would like to see that improved.
Me gustaría que se mejore eso.
裁判看到的第一张图像不应该是看起来触动他的图像。
The first image that the referee will see should not be the one that appears to touch him.
La primera imagen que va a ver el árbitro no tendría que ser esa que parece que lo toca.
我相信裁判必须看到整个图像，从那里，当裁判打开电视时，首先看到的是明显有触摸。
I believe that the referee has to see the entire image and from there, when the referee turns on the television, the first thing is that apparently there is a touch.
Yo creo que el árbitro tiene que ver la imagen entera y a partir de ahí, cuando el árbitro pone la televisión, la primera es que aparentemente hay un toque.
它可以改进，它总是发生，我总是说，在我看来，这是一个......
It can be improved, it has always happened, I have always said that it seems to me that it is a...
es mejorable, ha pasado siempre, siempre lo he dicho que me parece que es una...
我认为裁判有条件。
I think the referee conditions it.
Creo que el árbitro lo condiciona.
在游戏过程中，不是收集它，而是条件它。
During the game, not collecting it, that conditions it.
Durante el partido no cobrarlo, lo condiciona eso.
但这些是我不会改变的事情，但我认为这可能是需要改进的事情。
But they are things that I am not going to change, but I think it could be something to improve.
pero son cosas que yo no la voy a cambiar, pero creo que sí que podría ser una cosa a mejorar.
你向他们展示整个开始比赛，而不是第一个比赛，因为第一个比赛已经给你一种他们在呼唤你的感觉
that you show them the entire starting play and not the first one because the first one already gives you the feeling that they are calling you
que le muestres la jugada de inicio toda y no la primera porque la primera ya te da la sensación de que te están llamando
你必须收集它。
and you have to collect it.
y lo tenéis que cobrar.
但是嘿，就是这样，就是这样。
But hey, that's it, that's it.
Pero bueno, ya está, ya está.
这不是借口。
It's not an excuse.
No es una excusa.
有时，我再说一遍，它已经倒在了我们这边。
Sometimes, I repeat, it has fallen to our side.
A veces, repito, ha caído para nuestro lado.
这一次，他倒在了对手这边，就这样了。
This time he fell to the rival's side and that's it.
Esta vez cayó para el lado del rival y ya está.